{
    "questions":[
    {
      "question": "Which actor played the character of Tony Stark, also known as Iron Man, in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "options": [
          "Chris Hemsworth",
          "Robert Downey Jr.",
        "Chris Evans",
        "Mark Ruffalo"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is known for her role as Hermione Granger in the Harry Potter film series?",
      "options": [
          "Jennifer Lawrence",
          "Scarlett Johansson",
          "Emma Watson",
        "Natalie Portman"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which musician released the album 'Thriller', which is the best-selling album of all time?",
      "options": [
        "Michael Jackson",
        "Madonna",
        "Elvis Presley",
        "Prince"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the lead vocalist of the band Coldplay?",
      "options": [
        "Chris Martin",
        "Bono",
        "Dave Grohl",
        "Mick Jagger"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which actress won an Academy Award for her role in the movie 'La La Land'?",
      "options": [
          "Meryl Streep",
          "Cate Blanchett",
          "Nicole Kidman",
          "Emma Stone"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is credited as the founder of modern physics and formulated the theory of relativity?",
      "options": [
          "Isaac Newton",
          "Galileo Galilei",
          "Nikola Tesla",
          "Albert Einstein"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which philosopher is known for his work 'Meditations' and is considered one of the key figures in Western philosophy?",
      "options": [
          "Plato",
          "Marcus Aurelius",
        "Aristotle",
        "Socrates"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who wrote the book 'The Republic' and introduced the concept of the ideal state and philosopher-kings?",
      "options": [
          "Friedrich Nietzsche",
          "Immanuel Kant",
          "Plato",
        "Jean-Jacques Rousseau"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is often referred to as the 'Father of Modern Philosophy' and wrote the famous phrase 'Cogito, ergo sum' ('I think, therefore I am')?",
      "options": [
          "John Locke",
          "David Hume",
          "Ren√© Descartes",
        "Thomas Hobbes"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the author of 'The Communist Manifesto' and is considered one of the most influential figures in socialist philosophy?",
      "options": [
        "Karl Marx",
        "Friedrich Engels",
        "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Leon Trotsky"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which inventor and scientist is credited with developing the theory of alternating current (AC) and is known for his contributions to the field of electricity?",
      "options": [
          "Thomas Edison",
          "Alexander Graham Bell",
          "Benjamin Franklin",
          "Nikola Tesla"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the founder of psychoanalysis and developed theories about the unconscious mind, dreams, and the concept of the ego, superego, and id?",
      "options": [
        "Sigmund Freud",
        "Carl Jung",
        "Alfred Adler",
        "Jean Piaget"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which inventor and scientist is credited with developing the theory of alternating current (AC) and is known for his contributions to the field of electricity?",
      "options": [
        "Nikola Tesla",
        "Thomas Edison",
        "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Benjamin Franklin"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the founder of psychoanalysis and developed theories about the unconscious mind, dreams, and the concept of the ego, superego, and id?",
      "options": [
        "Sigmund Freud",
        "Carl Jung",
        "Alfred Adler",
        "Jean Piaget"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is considered the father of modern computer science and artificial intelligence and played a crucial role in breaking the Enigma code during World War II?",
      "options": [
          "Charles Babbage",
          "John von Neumann",
          "Alan Turing",
        "Tim Berners-Lee"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is known as the 'Father of the Constitution' and was the principal author of the United States Constitution?",
      "options": [
          "George Washington",
          "James Madison",
        "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Benjamin Franklin"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the founder of the modern nursing profession and established the first nursing school?",
      "options": [
        "Florence Nightingale",
        "Clara Barton",
        "Mary Seacole",
        "Dorothea Dix"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    }
]
}